<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anthony Zhou</title>
    <description>Psychology, Economics, Programming, or anything interesting.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 22:10:32 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 22:10:32 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Favorite Books of 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to think books were like drugs. And I don’t mean garden-variety pills like Benadryl or Tylenol–I’m talking hardcore drugs: nicotine, cocaine, and so on. How did I come to this conclusion? Like many kids, I would often start reading a book and struggle to put it down. I would start reading &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; in the morning and look up to find the sun was already setting. If addiction is a behavior where dependence on a substance interferes with a person’s ability to live a full life, my younger self was a full-blown pothead, if only for books instead of weed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was wrong about books. They’re not addictive drugs; instead, they’re more like food. I now believe in a more holistic way of thinking about information input and output, by imagining the ideas that come into my head are like ingredients in a blender. Podcasts. Magazines. Movies. Books. &lt;em&gt;Kerplunk&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;BZHHHH&lt;/em&gt;. And out comes a smoothie of new and interesting ideas. This way, books come out looking like a relatively nutritious option (at least compared to TV shows and Instagram feeds).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that to say, I decided to compile a list of the books I most enjoyed reading this year. Treat this as a list of ingredients, a diverse set of raw materials that can help you achieve a result that is both tasty and nutritious (and they might inspire you to read, too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-nonfiction&quot;&gt;General nonfiction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/em&gt; – Daniel Kahneman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/em&gt; – Nassim Nicholas Taleb&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Master Algorithm&lt;/em&gt; – Pedro Domingos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scale&lt;/em&gt; – Geoffrey West&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business&quot;&gt;Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How I Built This&lt;/em&gt; – Guy Raz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Innovator’s Dilemma&lt;/em&gt; – Clayton Christensen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;memoir&quot;&gt;Memoir&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Educated&lt;/em&gt; – Tara Westover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Writing&lt;/em&gt; – Stephen King&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-help&quot;&gt;Self-help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&lt;/em&gt; – Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/em&gt; – Dale Carnegie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;When&lt;/em&gt; – Daniel Pink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fiction&quot;&gt;Fiction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Remains of the Day&lt;/em&gt; – Kazuo Ishiguro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Alchemist&lt;/em&gt; – Paulo Coehlo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt; – F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt; – Cormac McCarthy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn&lt;/em&gt; – Mark Twain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bell Jar&lt;/em&gt; – Sylvia Plath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve read any of these books or have other recommendations, feel free to leave a comment below, or drop me a line at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:azhou.blog@gmail.com&quot;&gt;azhou.blog@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/book-recommendations-2020/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/book-recommendations-2020/</guid>
        
        <category>list</category>
        
        
        <category>books</category>
        
        <category>reading</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Two Sides of Liupanshui</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Liupanshui is a city of incredible contrast. On one side is the “capital of cool” — a clean modern summer home for visitors escaping the heat of the big cities in the East of China. Go through a tunnel, however, and you are thrust into a different world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you’ll notice is the air. Old Liupanshui is a steel town, and the air hangs thick with soot. Flecks of coal, ranging from microscopic to corn-flake size, transform the sky into a soupy sort of oatmeal. Once a major employer, the local steel company has taken a hard hit in recent years, burdened by the unprecedented rise of automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We coast through the unkempt streets in a sleek Honda CR-V — my brother and I, my mother and her sister — searching for the past. At last we arrive. In the span of a couple dozen years, the landscape has mutated so that the dilapidated buildings are now hundreds of feet from the road, barely visible through the thick smog. But the corrugated metal roofs and the ancient wooden walls reveal their identity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the site of my mother’s childhood home. We pull off to the shoulder and snap a few photos. Then we pile back in the car. As we drive on, my mom regales us with tales of the past. when they were little, she and my aunt would have to make tea to cover up the flavor of water, because it was tainted thick with charcoal and chemicals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A familiar whistle makes my ears perk up. A train! We park the car and venture out to a landing that overlooks a chasm where overburdened trains lug sloughs of coal, rumbling on their rusty tracks. But the incredible size of the trains is not what captures my attention. On the landing, a ring of spectators gather round a small, raised pavilion — what could they be up to? I wander over to the wall of humanity and stand on tiptoe to get a peek. I catch a glimpse of dice and a small wad of cash on the table — all the trappings of a game, and yet the spectators’ faces are frozen like stone. A couple weatherworn faces turn towards me silently, their ragged clothes and deep wrinkles screaming “you don’t belong here.” I turn away and walk, quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my hurry to get away, I nearly run headlong into a group of kids playing a game of Chinese jump rope — like cat’s cradle, but played with legs instead of fingers. Their faces, darkened by soot, shine brightly, full of joy and wonder and whimsy. In the midst of apparent poverty and desolation, not to mention rising unemployment, they smile and laugh as they try to untangle the rope tied between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while, I marvel at these carefree children. Then I turn to the disillusioned rabble of gamblers. Back and forth, back and forth. I study myself, an intruder from the world of white tablecloths and privilege and books and books and books. The rumble of the trains fades into the distance, and all I can hear is the sweet laughter of the children, blending with the raucous cry of a triumphant gambler and the murmur of my mother and aunt’s wistful reflections on this place now foreign to them. The sounds swirl together, young and old, rich and poor, past and present, as a symphony of colors. For just that moment, the gap between us all had shrunk from a gaping canyon to nearly nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2020/10/liupanshui_railroad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of Liupanshui railroads&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em style=&quot;display: block; font-size: 0.75em&quot;&gt;Liupanshui railroads, used to transport coal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we returned to the “capital of cool,” which, while not without its own problems, is a world apart from the soot-stained old town. As I looked around, however, the new town seemed different somehow. The clean-swept roads and gleaming shopping center now icons of impossible perfection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that, despite our shiny new cars and quiet suburban houses and Fourth of July neighborhood barbecues, we are all the children and grandchildren of the disadvantaged. Inequality is a reality that we all too often tuck under the rug and seldom see in the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day in the city of incredible contrast, I discovered a new perspective and a better way forward. To watch. To listen. To empathize.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/liupanshui-capital-of-cool/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/liupanshui-capital-of-cool/</guid>
        
        <category>liupanshui</category>
        
        <category>china</category>
        
        <category>inequality</category>
        
        
        <category>narrative</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Built a Semi-Automated Matching System for Big &amp; Mini</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I co-founded Big &amp;amp; Mini in early April, as a nonprofit organization dedicated to combatting social isolation and creating virtual connections by matching older and younger people for video calls. Since then, the platform has taken off, featured in media outlets like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houstonchronicle.com/techburger/article/seniors-teens-coronavirus-social-distance-online-15228449.php?utm_campaign=tbgr&quot;&gt;The Houston Chronicle&lt;/a&gt; and we are continuously updating our technology to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As co-founder and CTO, I helped create a system where users can sign up and get matched to a Big or a Mini through our website, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigandmini.org&quot;&gt;https://bigandmini.org&lt;/a&gt;. This is my report describing the latest major release of our technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big &amp;amp; Mini 2.0 is now live!&lt;/strong&gt; It’s similar to the previous system, but more automated. In this report, I will share the reasoning behind this change, as well as an explanation of how the new system works. Our major new features are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An automated training quiz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated matching system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the initial version of Big &amp;amp; Mini, our team was spending too much time manually verifying training completion and making matches. Automation fixes both of these issues. Here’s how the system works. When they sign up, new users are sent to a staging area. Then, after verifying their email address and completing the training quiz, they are added to the pool of new users ready for a match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a week on Sunday, a system administrator will press a button to trigger automatic matching for the upcoming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;training-quiz&quot;&gt;Training Quiz&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The training quiz is pretty straightforward — answer all the questions correctly, and you have completed training. The multiple-choice questions on this quiz, based on our training documents, replace the short-answer Google Form we were using previously. Now, instead of asking a human reviewer to spend time reading through the same answers over and over again, the quiz answers are automatically graded by the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;automated-matching&quot;&gt;Automated Matching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the magic happens — in our new automated matching system, we use an algorithm that can achieve even better results than a human matcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out matching is not a trivial problem. To illustrate my point, consider this simple example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Bigs&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Minis&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 10am&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A, B, C&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;D, E, F, G, H, I&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 2pm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;J, K, L&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;D, E, F&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A naive approach would be to match people up as we get to them (a greedy algorithm). But this would give us 3 matches for 10 am (A &amp;amp; D, B &amp;amp; E, C &amp;amp; F) and no matches for 2 pm, leaving out 6 of our 12 Bigs and Minis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were asked to do the matching, how would you do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, if you look closely, you’ll notice there’s a way to make sure everyone gets matched:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Bigs&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Minis&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 10am&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;G&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 10am&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;H&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 10am&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 2pm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;J&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 2pm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;K&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;E&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday 2pm&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;L&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all twelve of our Bigs &amp;amp; Minis will get to make a meaningful intergenerational connection right away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we go about solving this matching problem? Previously, we had a human administrator look through all the users who needed matches (much as you just did) and searched for the optimal solution by hand. As you might expect, this system did not work perfectly, and we ended up leaving out some of our Bigs &amp;amp; Minis. With Big &amp;amp; Mini 2.0, however, we have a new way of doing things: with an algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The algorithm, coded in Java, works as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Construct a weighted graph with Bigs &amp;amp; Minis as nodes.
 a. The weights correspond to the number of connections a Big or a Mini has with another Big or Mini.
 b. Edges are stored in an adjacency list&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the same time, construct a list storing the number of edges each node has.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sort the list of edge counts in increasing order.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the node(s) with the least number of edges:
 a. Sort the list of nodes by weight and pick the one with the lowest weighted edge (the least number of possible matches with a given Big/Mini).
 b. Put this match onto a separate list as a pair and remove them from the main adjacency list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat step 4 until there are no remaining nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this algorithm, we end up maximizing the number of matches, by matching the least available people first. Because of the flexibility of this approach, we could even change the weights of the edges to account for factors like common interests or geographic proximity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelzhao.xyz/about&quot;&gt;Michael Zhao&lt;/a&gt; for writing this algorithm and Grace Liu for implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the algorithm returns a list of matches, the matched Bigs &amp;amp; Minis are removed from the staging area and given their matches with an initial time and meeting link, which will automatically show up on their Big &amp;amp; Mini dashboard. When the matches have finished processing, the browser automatically downloads a CSV containing the automatic matches made this week, for the convenience of the system administrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By automating the boring administrative parts of the job, Big &amp;amp; Mini 2.0 frees up our team to focus on more important things, like interacting with our users and making sure our Bigs &amp;amp; Minis have the best experience they possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://bigandmini.org/whatsnewpage/ourposts/engineeringPost&quot;&gt;on the Big &amp;amp; Mini website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/bigandmini-automated-matching/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/bigandmini-automated-matching/</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>javascript</category>
        
        <category>java</category>
        
        <category>aws</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to be Productive This Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you want to accomplish this summer break? Let’s say you want to do something meaningful. And yet, you may find that the weeks start to blur by without your accomplishing anything, and as soon as you know it summer will be over. The most rewarding goals require that you schedule time to sit down and get to work. If you’re like me, scheduling time to do hard things is easier said than done, but behavioral science research has yielded some answers that might make our lives a little bit easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what it is you might want to do — learn a new language, write a book, or improve your cooking skills — being productive will require you to set aside focused time each day to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired in part by Dan Pink’s book &lt;em&gt;When: the scientific secrets of perfect timing&lt;/em&gt;, I have compiled a daily schedule designed to optimize your performance, based on recent behavioral science research. This exact schedule will not work for everyone — it’s tailored for students like me with a particular kind of sleep schedule (which I’m told is relatively early) — but I hope this provides a good model to build upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-schedule&quot;&gt;The schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;715-am--wake-up&quot;&gt;7:15 am — Wake up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleeping makes us dehydrated, so Pink recommends we down a glass of water right after getting up. If you are hungry, eat a light snack of healthy carbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;730-am--exercise&quot;&gt;7:30 am — Exercise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercising, for most people, increases alertness, allowing you to perform at your best for the rest of the day. Also, it’s a healthy habit, and habits are easiest to keep when done in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;830-am--breakfast&quot;&gt;8:30 am — Breakfast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;900-am--begin-deep-work&quot;&gt;9:00 am — Begin Deep Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep work&lt;/em&gt; is a uninterrupted period of work that requires intense focus and creates value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unfamiliar with the concept of deep work, Cal Newport defines the concept in his groundbreaking book &lt;em&gt;Deep Work&lt;/em&gt;. The book explains how deep work is essential to thriving in the modern economy, and how you can implement deep work in your own life. For the purpose of this schedule, consider this a time for the most intellectually demanding tasks of your day. Take breaks as needed, but make sure they are restorative: checking social media or your email inbox during this time can derail your focus and leave you feeling drained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1200-pm--lunch&quot;&gt;12:00 pm — Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;100-pm--walk&quot;&gt;1:00 pm — Walk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most people, the two hours after lunch are the most unproductive of the day. It’s the dreaded mid-afternoon slump, and it’s a good time to perform tasks that are less cognitively demanding, like listening to a podcast or walking the dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research increasingly supports the fact that walking is beneficial to physiological and psychological health. An hour might be a long time to walk, but in a time of remote work and school, this can take the place of a one-hour commute. As Geoffrey West points out in his book &lt;em&gt;Scale: The Universal Laws of Life and Death in Organisms, Cities and Companies&lt;/em&gt;, a roughly one-hour commute time has held constant for humanity throughout history, whether we are farmers walking to the village or suburbanites driving to the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;200-pm--shallow-work&quot;&gt;2:00 pm — Shallow work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, this is the time to answer emails and check social media. While both activities are necessary, they are not cognitively demanding, and generally don’t help us learn new skills or create lots of value. Using this hour to handle emails and other odds-and-ends helps assure that digital communications don’t seep into other parts of your day and diminish your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;300-pm--nap&quot;&gt;3:00 pm — Nap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naps are most effective when they are 10-20 minutes long, before you enter deep sleep. Dan Pink typically sets a 25 minute nap timer, because it takes most people around 7 minutes to fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;330-pm--medium-work&quot;&gt;3:30 pm — Medium work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you think of a better name for it, but many of the things we do are not demanding enough to be considered deep work, nor are they as simple as sending emails and text messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;600-pm--dinner&quot;&gt;6:00 pm — Dinner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieticians usually recommend that we eat dinner around 4-6 hours before going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;700-pm--relax&quot;&gt;7:00 pm — Relax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great time to hang out (virtually?) with friends. In general, our moods will be happier but we may not have enough brainpower to work on things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1000-pm--read-a-book&quot;&gt;10:00 pm — Read a book&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1100-pm--sleep&quot;&gt;11:00 pm — Sleep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;## A Caveat
 According to Dan Pink, this type of schedule does not work for one particular group of people: night owls. Teenagers and young adults, in fact, are especially likely to be owls. But before you immediately jump to conclusions, here’s Dan Pink’s 3 step formula for testing your chronotype:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a day when you can sleep whenever you want, when do you usually sleep?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On a day when you can wake up whenever you want, when do you usually wake up?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the midpoint of those two times? (if I sleep at 12 am and wake up at 8 am, then my midpoint of sleep would be 4 am)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Pink demonstrates that most people are not larks or owls, but a third type of bird, which he calls — you guessed it — “third birds.” In general, people’s midpoints of sleep are distributed along a bell curve, with most people (60-70%) falling in the middle (roughly 3:30 - 5:30 am). Most of us are third birds. The further your midpoint of sleep falls from the center of this group, the less likely traditional schedules will work for you. If you’re interested in learning more about chronotypes, I highly recommend Dan Pink’s book, which takes a deeper dive into recent research on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this schedule may not work for everyone, it serves as a starting point for planning a productive day. After following the schedule for a while, I’ve come to enjoy the sense of accomplishment at having finished difficult tasks in the morning, giving me the freedom to relax without feeling guilty. If you follow a different schedule or tried out this one, leave a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/daily-schedule/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/daily-schedule/</guid>
        
        <category>scheduling</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
        <category>planning</category>
        
        
        <category>tutorials</category>
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What does media sensationalism say about our ability to fight pandemics?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Chaos. Everything I see is a blur of red and gray: people in the streets doubled over in pain, hacking up fresh crimson blood, ambulances rushing back and forth, only serving to move the bodies from one hellish place to another; and the uninfected, hoping that if they walk fast enough the horror will never catch up with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a scene from a movie, but I can’t quite remember what it’s about — maybe I’ll think of it later. I switch off the television and nearly jump in shock at what I hear next in the real world, right at this moment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, my ears adjust. Through the open window, I begin to hear again. The serenity of the neighborhood’s sounds are comforting: the call of a mockingbird, the gentle bubbling of a creek, and the giggles of children as they struggle to rein in their new puppies while wearing rollerblades. The weather is marvelous, and a gentle breeze wafts by me with the scent of fresh blossoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gentle hope of springtime leads me to start thinking and asking questions. I sit down to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this historic moment, many of us are experiencing a confusing dichotomy of information: on one side, the media bombards us with warnings and horror and acute respiratory distress syndrome. Meanwhile, the reality of living in isolation, at least for those of us in suburbia, is almost unnervingly peaceful. What can we make of this disparity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it reflects our desire for sensationalist content. As the notable psychologist Daniel Kahneman has pointed out, our brains value coherence over statistical facts. In an increasingly competitive industry, even our most trusted news sources have no choice but to tell increasingly visceral stories, at the expense of more rational viewpoints. However, their attempts to remain relevant are rooted in a desire to share necessary information, a task they fulfill admirably. Journalists help us make sense of an overly complex world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the disconnect: from hunter-gatherers eaten by lions to medieval serfs being beaten to death, we are born from a place of violence. Yet the world we are born into is safer than ever before, across the board, from criminal justice to modern medicine. The reminders of death and suffering, so frequent we become desensitized, are just a small red blotch on the large white canvas of the world: as we work to address the startling horror of this new disease, we must take moments to step back and take in the remarkable tranquility of our world, to see how far we’ve come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pause the television for a moment and listen to the silence. Only then will you begin to hear again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, we’ve got plenty of problems left to solve: disease, war, and climate change, to name a few. And some have it much worse than others — inequality is a vice that must be ended. But, as history demonstrates, we have endless reasons to be hopeful, to realize that the disparity between television violence and real-world tranquility is a blessing for hope in our long and dangerous fight against this virus. The same gap should make us resolve to help in any way possible, because the marvels of modern innovation have shown us what can be accomplished through collective social action. Instead of helplessness or indifference, those of us who experience peace during these unprecedented times can channel hope and optimism to make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember what the movie was about now. It tells a story of finding the bright side in a seemingly desolate world. It’s a movie about hope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/covid-media-silence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/covid-media-silence/</guid>
        
        <category>coronavirus</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>optimism</category>
        
        
        <category>media</category>
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get Involved: Open Source Technology Fighting COVID-19</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this document is to provide a guide to the open source initiatives working to fight the novel coronavirus (COVID-19). Read on if you would like to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open source technology&lt;/strong&gt; refers to projects where the source code is freely available to the public, many of which would welcome anyone who can contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in contributing, see if these projects have issues in their GitHub repositories or other tasks that you might be able to help with. If you don’t think you have enough technical expertise, help spread the word! See if any of your friends and family might be able to help out with open source (1) Software or (2) Hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-software&quot;&gt;1. Software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the table below you will find a few open source projects to contribute to/look at. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/soroushchehresa/awesome-coronavirus&quot;&gt;Here is a more complete list&lt;/a&gt; (note that the projects with more stars are probably more impactful and better to contribute to).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Project Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Objective&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Language&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Demo&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CHIME: Covid-19 Hospital Impact Model for Epidemics&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Estimates the resources needed for hospitals (# of patients requiring ICUs, ventilation, etc.) for capacity planning.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Python&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CodeForPhilly/chime/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://penn-chime.phl.io/&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Locale.ai Covid-19 live visualization&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Visualizes the pandemic using open source data.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;JavaScript (Vue.js)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/localeai/covid19-live-visualization&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://covid19.locale.ai/&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tokyo Covid-19 Task Force Website&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Official government website for all information about Covid-19 in Tokyo.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;JavaScript (Node.js)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tokyo-metropolitan-gov/covid19&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stopcovid19.metro.tokyo.lg.jp/&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Novel Coronavirus Dataset (from JHU CSSE)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Largest available official dataset of Covid-19 cases.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19&quot;&gt;Dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.arcgis.com/apps/opsdashboard/index.html#/bda7594740fd40299423467b48e9ecf6&quot;&gt;Visualization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-hardware&quot;&gt;2. Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably even more important than software right now is open source hardware. Current projects include low-cost ventilators, PCR tools, and distributed computing. Whether you’re a designer, builder, or anything in between, these projects could use your help! Contributing is not as standardized as with software, so I’d suggest you go join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/duAtG5h&quot;&gt;Open Hardware Summit Discord Server&lt;/a&gt; to find out how you can help (they have a #covid-19 channel).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an introduction to some of the biggest projects going on right now, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.com/article/20/3/open-hardware-covid19&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and best of luck contributing. Stay safe out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Anthony Zhou, open source advocate&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/covid-19-open-source-technology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/covid-19-open-source-technology/</guid>
        
        <category>coronavirus</category>
        
        <category>COVID-19</category>
        
        <category>open source</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Sustainability Makes Economic Sense</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We are on the edge of a fundamental reshaping of finance.”&lt;br /&gt;
– Larry Fink, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This January, BlackRock CEO Larry Fink announced in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackrock.com/corporate/investor-relations/larry-fink-ceo-letter&quot;&gt;annual letter to CEOs&lt;/a&gt; that climate change needs to be a major priority of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BlackRock – and by extension Larry Fink – manages nearly &lt;em&gt;$7 trillion&lt;/em&gt; in investments, making it the largest asset manager in the world. With a proven track record as an astute financial advisor, the billionaire is a trusted voice in the world of business. If he says we should protect the climate, he is not acting as a tree-hugging hippie but as a representative of his clients’ financial interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, Fink is saying that it makes financial sense for a company to invest in sustainability. To me, this was counterintuitive. Although I certainly hope we can slow climate change, I had always assumed that the profit models for companies that damage the environment demanded exploitation, even though such a model would be unsustainable in the long term. In other words, I thought that short-term interests will trump long-term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-tragedy-of-the-commons&quot;&gt;The Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would I and so many others think so lowly of companies? For me, this was a classic case of William Lloyd’s &lt;em&gt;Tragedy of the Commons&lt;/em&gt;. If you’ve never heard of it, here is a brief example: in Lloyd’s time (1833), English villagers customarily shared a piece of land where all their cattle grazed. Lloyd hypothesized that if one villager let too many cattle graze on the land, overgrazing would result. The renegade villager would profit greatly in the short term from owning so many cows, at the expense of the pasture’s long-term health. What if the other herders decide to do the same, so they can continue to profit? After a few years of this, the common would be completely destroyed, just because each one of the villagers made the individually rational decision to allow more cattle graze in the common. Wikipedia has &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons#Examples&quot;&gt;a great list of similar examples in the real world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Cows_on_Selsley_Common.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cows on a pasture&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em style=&quot;display: block; font-size: 0.75em&quot;&gt;Cows on a typical English common. (Image: Sharon Loxton / Cows on Selsley Common)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not hard to see how the same tragedy of the commons can apply to environmental destruction. In a capitalist economy, companies act in their economic self-interest, using up resources like coal and oil and forests and fish and even water. Abusing natural resources gives companies a clear competitive advantage over others who attempt to protect the environment. To a large extent, this is the economic dynamic that has caused rampant environmental destruction in the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about climate change? At first glance, the tragedy of the commons seems to fit perfectly: the corporations are the herders, their manufacturing processes are the cattle, and the grass is the carbon they are releasing into the atmosphere, causing global warming. Unsustainable manufacturing processes are simply more profitable. Any company that tries to slow climate change is either just giving lip service for PR or is bound to fail, and even governments fall into the same trap as they compete for the investments of multinational corporations – climate change is inevitable and the world is going to burn! Tragedy of the Commons, QED!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that would be the case, except for one eccentric group of people: investors. Most investors, like Larry Fink, are not interested in the success of individual companies, but rather in the success of their portfolios as a whole, over the long term. It just so happens that investors control many of the world’s largest companies, because the investors provide their lifeblood: money. So it’s not exactly right to say that companies are always interested in short-term profitability. In fact, they are interested in whatever their stakeholders happen to be interested in, and for the past few decades the answer was always short-term profitability. But the tide is turning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidence is beginning to pile on for researchers who argue that climate change will fundamentally undermine the way our economy and society work. For investors, the evidence points to a simple axiom: &lt;strong&gt;climate risk is investment risk.&lt;/strong&gt; As Fink describes in his 2020 letter to CEOs, climate change touches nearly every building block of the modern economy, including municipal bonds, the 30-year mortgage, inflation, interest rates, and even emerging markets where extreme heat causes productivity to decline. It throws a wrench into every economic model and growth projection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many investors are beginning to ask themselves whether it is still safe to invest in unsustainable practices. Perhaps even more than the rest of us, investors have a clear economic stake in avoiding climate risk: to protect the long-term sustainability of their portfolios. As a result, companies are starting to embrace sustainability disclosures and frameworks for managing environmental issues. Close scrutiny is still needed, but the foundations are in place for a revolutionary shift towards sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-implications-of-investor-incentives&quot;&gt;The Implications of Investor Incentives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get lost in the complicated turns of logic and the cascading of incentives, but the takeaway from Fink’s letter is simply that there is now a strong economic incentive to invest in sustainability. In other words, perhaps for the first time in history, environmentalism is no longer a conflict between economic and moral interests – it is a collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such a critical point that I think it’s worth repeating:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Perhaps for the first time in history, environmentalism is no longer a conflict between economic and moral interests – it is a collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why Fink’s letter has given me hope for the Earth’s climate. While certainly touching, moralizing and guilt-tripping have clearly been ineffective methods of catalyzing change, despite the impressive efforts of climate activists. Finally, economics has given us a real way out, a tangible answer to the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that everything is okay or that we should stop caring about the climate. In fact, human-caused climate change has already caused irreversible damage to the planet. Rather, having an economic understanding of climate change should give us motivation to pursue climate activism even more strongly, scrutinizing corporate sustainability disclosures and demanding environmentally conscious actions, because we know our actions have a real economic impact. As the evidence piles on, growing numbers of people are beginning to realize that the economic impact of climate change will be a net negative. Simply put,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability makes economic sense.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/climate-change-economic-sustainability/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/climate-change-economic-sustainability/</guid>
        
        <category>climate change</category>
        
        <category>investment</category>
        
        <category>sustainability</category>
        
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
        <category>economics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Dealings with Museum Security in Florence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a blistering hot day in Florence, part of the record-breaking heat wave of 2019. The kind of day where, despite the thick white coat of sunscreen I lathered on layer by layer, my normally tan skin shone the same red-orange hue of the tomato sauce in pizza margherita. In fact, just a few sprigs of basil would complete the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Florence is a beautiful city. It would have been so easy to fall into a heat-induced daze, to sink into the soft plush clouds nestled against the pure blue sky and lose all sense of time and place and direction. But to do so would be fatal—the scammers were at the top of their game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my dog, our family’s backyard is his outhouse. My mother likes to call them &lt;em&gt;dilei&lt;/em&gt;, land mines. Finding my way through the grass makes me feel a bit like Tom Cruise in Mission Impossible. It wasn’t until going to Florence that I realized the value of this daily practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our daytime tour of the city, the Florentian scammers demonstrated what I must admit is an ingenious strategy: they would cover the street with a tapestry of prints, featuring landmarks like the Leaning Tower, the Cathedral of Santa Maria, and the Baptistery of Saint John. The prints, obviously of cheap quality and mass produced, stretched across the street, covering nearly all of the age-worn cobblestones of the old town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this in the hopes that some hapless, naive (and probably American) tourist would step on one of these prints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“20 euros! 20 euros!” The shout startled me from my ruminations. A scamster had ensnared a member of our tour group. Judging by the victim’s face during this exchange, his brain was in conflict. On one hand, the American values of trust and minding your own business demanded that he compensate the merchant for his damaged merchandise. On the other hand, this was not America and no one was guaranteed to play by American rules. I watched to see what he would do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, he paid up. For these Florentian scammers, fear was probably the greatest factor in their ability to convert innocent tourists into lucrative assets. Fear of being in an unknown place with unknown people and language and customs and who knows what could happen if I do something wrong and suddenly the police and the mafia and the carabinieri are after me what do I do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fear is not the only lesson I learned from the scammers. In fact, I noticed that these people were actually masterful artists, crafting alternate realities out of thin air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, these Florentians had perfected the craft of subjective truth. That afternoon, subjective truth is exactly what I decided to apply with a security guard at the Accademia Gallery in Florence, a museum featuring Michelangelo’s David. All I wanted was to keep my water and my reusable water bottle. Should be a piece of cake, right? Not so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a museum of great stature, the gallery prides itself on airtight security. As a result, part of the airport-style entry rules forbids beverage containers with a capacity of 1.5 liters or more. I, being a connoisseur of fine beverages, had with me a half-full 1.5 liter bottle of refreshing sparkling water, along with a reusable bottle of possibly suspicious tap water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I realized I needed to take action, immediately. In my backpack were a reusable bottle (smaller than 1.5 liters) filled with water I did not need to keep, along with a single-use bottle (1.5 liters) filled with water that I needed as hydration for the remaining half of that sweltering day. Logically, then, I should empty out the reusable bottle and fill it with sparkling water, dispensing the 1.5 liter bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my plan appeared foolproof, I forgot to account for one glaring fact: the security guard spoke even less English than I could speak Italian. To give you a sense of my knowledge of Italian, my vocabulary is limited to just a few words: &lt;em&gt;buon giorno&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;andiamo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;pizza margherita&lt;/em&gt;. How would it be possible to convey any sense of truth without a common language?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The museum security had graciously provided a receptacle for these unwanted beverage containers, in the form of a cardboard box with a trash bag stretched over it. By this time, it was already filled with bottles of all denominations, some left partially open and leaking. I wanted to get rid of the water in my reusable bottle. I wanted to keep the water in the larger bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I poured the water into the cardboard box. Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What followed was bedlam: the security guard exploded into a vicious verbal tirade, ridiculing my unprecedented stupidity. Hearing the commotion, the neighboring security guard joined him in his outraged comments, also in Italian. All eyes in the room turned towards me, some with expressions of disgust and others with quiet sympathy. Apparently, I had done something terribly wrong, though I couldn’t understand what it could have been. But I wasn’t done yet—I still had to transfer the water from my larger bottle into the now-empty reusable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It must have taken no more than five seconds. And yet, the seconds it took to refill my water bottle slowed the rushing river of time to the pace of a half-frozen, mushy creek in the winter. Meanwhile, despite the museum’s ample air-conditioning system, my ears began to redden as I absorbed the heat shooting at me from the security guards’ incomprehensible insults and the crowd’s inexplicable attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the moment was finished. With a satisfying &lt;em&gt;click!&lt;/em&gt;, I screwed tight and shut the water bottle, replaced it in my bag, and continued into the museum with red ears, feigning deafness to the enraged shouts of the guards that still echoed off the walls behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on this moment now, I realize it may have been a mistake to pour the water into the box, even though it didn’t hurt anyone. I have now concluded that some knowledge of Italian would have been necessary to avoid completely misunderstanding the situation. What do you think? Leave a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/florence-incident/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/florence-incident/</guid>
        
        <category>italy</category>
        
        <category>florence</category>
        
        <category>language</category>
        
        
        <category>narrative</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can we achieve symbiosis with machines? Neuralink and Facebook try to answer the question.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today’s internet-enabled devices are competing for our attention, all the time. What if there was some way we could escape the loop of digital addiction? What if we could become one with our machines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the Brain-Machine Interface (BMI), also known as a brain-computer interface (BCI), mind-machine interface (MMI), or direct neural interface (DNI): a device that translates neural signals into commands that control hardware or software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The premise is simple. Currently, we interface with technology, and the outside world in general, through low-bandwidth options like keyboards and speech. For argument’s sake, assume that your words-per-minute (WPM) when speaking is 150 (about average, according to the National Center for Voice and Speech), and that your WPM when typing is 75 (you can get a rough estimate of your typing speed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://thetypingcat.com/typing-speed-test/1m&quot;&gt;this minute-long test&lt;/a&gt;). Compare that with your brain, a highly efficient computer that may have as many as 50 processes running at the same time, as noted in this article from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/532291/fmri-data-reveals-the-number-of-parallel-processes-running-in-the-brain/&quot;&gt;the MIT Technology Review&lt;/a&gt;. Each one of us has a brain full of countless ideas and connections that never make it out into the real world, due simply to the ridiculously slow rate of communication between our powerful brains and the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about how much time the average American spends on any kind of technology. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/melanie-curtin/are-you-on-your-phone-too-much-average-person-spends-this-many-hours-on-it-every-day.html&quot;&gt;According to Inc magazine&lt;/a&gt;, the answer is &lt;em&gt;over four hours&lt;/em&gt;. Our society is just beginning to realize the way digital overload can isolate us from nature and the people closest to us, but becoming a hermit and moving to a cabin in the woods doesn’t seem so feasible. Is there any way we could use technology to enhance our lives rather than distracting from them? This is the vision Facebook Reality Labs has for its Brain-Computer Interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook-reality-labs&quot;&gt;Facebook Reality Labs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine a world where all the knowledge, fun, and utility of today’s smartphones were instantly accessible and completely hands-free. Where you could spend quality time with the people who matter most in your life, whenever you want, no matter where in the world you happen to be. And where you could connect with others in a meaningful way, regardless of external distractions, geographic constraints, and even physical disabilities and limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July of 2019, Facebook Reality Labs released &lt;a href=&quot;https://tech.fb.com/imagining-a-new-interface-hands-free-communication-without-saying-a-word/&quot;&gt;this report&lt;/a&gt; detailing some cutting edge work with the BCI. The lab sponsored a group of University of California, San Francisco (UCSF) researchers who are working to help patients with neurological diseases like ALS use brain-computer interfaces to communicate. BCI technology, as the report notes, is not new: it already helps people “feed themselves, hold the hand of a loved one, and even fly a jet simulator.” So why don’t we all have computers in our brains? There are two limiting factors in BCI development: speed and invasiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;talking-fast-and-talking-slow-balancing-speed-and-invasiveness-in-bmis&quot;&gt;Talking fast and talking slow: balancing speed and invasiveness in BMIs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emily Mugler, an engineer on the Facebook Reality Labs BCI team, describes how the conventional approach of electroencephalography (EEG), where a cap of electrodes is placed on the subjects head, was just not fast enough for patients with ALS to communicate their ideas effectively. “It sometimes took 70 minutes for a patient to type a single sentence,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, some labs attempted using electrocorticography (ECoG), which was faster but required a surgical operation inserting electrodes into the brain. Herein lies the problem that plagued past attempts to develop an effective BCI: fast technologies tend to be too invasive, whereas noninvasive solutions tend to be too slow. Researchers found themselves perplexed with the problem of getting inside the brain without physically getting inside the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook Reality Labs, together with the lab at UCSF, plans to solve this problem with near-infrared light: by beaming harmless light waves into the subject’s brain, a wearable device can sense blood oxygenation—much like in an fMRI (functional magnetic resonance imaging) machine—and use the measurements to guess at brain activity. While the system is currently “bulky, slow, and unreliable,” the UCSF researchers have successfully converted thoughts to words in real time and hope to reach a speed of 100 words per minute on a 1000 word vocabulary with an error of less than 17% (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-10994-4&quot;&gt;Read more in their &lt;em&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/em&gt; journal article&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are promising. Within a decade we might see keyboards by and large replaced by brain-machine interfaces, bringing us into a world where we could spend our lives connecting with others in a meaningful way, enabled by rather than encumbered by technology. But the universal adoption of BCIs raises serious issues of privacy. Can privacy even exist when our inner thoughts are exposed to the public? Moreover, Facebook is not the company many would most trust to safeguard their personal information, given its recent scandals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear not, for Facebook is not the only one developing this technology: Elon Musk has founded a company developing the Neuralink, a brain-machine interface with no qualms about physically invading your brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;neuralink---elon-musk&quot;&gt;Neuralink - Elon Musk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk’s justification for the need for a brain-machine interface goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You could sort of think of humanity as a biological bootloader for digital superintelligence
— Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, “bootloader” refers to the small piece of code needed to start up a computer. To explain this idea further, let’s examine the recent trends in artificial intelligence, as viewed in a Muskian mindset:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI is set to overtake humanity as the next stage in the evolution of consciousness. We’ll have gone from amoebas to lizards to chimps to humans to machines. Or something like that. Scary, right? While the truth of Musk’s statement is debatable, the underlying trend rings true: artificial intelligence, and technology in general, is expanding to replace many traditionally human tasks, from manufacturing to truck driving to being a cashier at McDonald’s. How can we escape the ultimate supremacy of AI?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is that we integrate the machines into ourselves, so that we can work together with our revolutionary technology rather than competing against it. A brain-machine interface would help us both drastically increase our productivity and avoid becoming obsolete. If you subscribe to Musk’s view of the inevitable march of technology (detailed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3lUEnMaiAU&quot;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;), we have two options: brain-machine interface or extinction as AI takes over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the Neuralink work? By inserting tiny electrodes linked to wires with diameter of 4-6 microns, or less than a quarter of the thickness of a typical human hair. The procedure goes like this: drill a 2 mm hole in the subject’s brain, then use a “sewing machine” to weave up to 96 tiny threads into the brain, creating 3,072 channels. As with all things Elon, Musk plans to push the Neuralink forward at a rapid pace, starting human clinical trials by the end of 2020, focusing on brain diseases, and envisioning widespread adoption in 4 to 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds scary because it is. With apparently little regard to the potential brain damage incurred by invasive surgery, the Neuralink in its current state creates two major health risks: glial scarring and broken electrodes. Glial scarring refers to scarring in the brain tissue that can inhibit communication and represents a reaction to serious brain damage. Meanwhile, the small electrodes used by the Neuralink are impossible to extract if broken, meaning they’ll just be stuck in the patient’s brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musk offers a compelling vision of the future—one in which we have achieved a “symbiosis with machines”—but the Neuralink’s radical approach to and bold vision for the BMI may end up rushing to offer the world a half-cooked dish that leaves us a little sick to the stomach. Whether or not the technical and health-related challenges are resolved, the Muskian view would tell us that the need to stay relevant in a world of increasing automation outweighs the health risks incurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happens-next&quot;&gt;What happens next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any technology, the brain-machine interface has great benefits and drawbacks that will affect people unequally, although both the utopian and dystopian views are probably overstated. In the end, many of our fears will probably be nullified as the technology improves and as a lack of privacy becomes the new normal. After all, the subjective truths of today, like privacy, may not hold steady even ten years into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And China’s going to do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what, it remains essential that the public holds Facebook, Neuralink, and the smorgasbord of BMI startups accountable, to ensure we don’t rush blindly into a technology without asking ourselves whether it truly makes the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading-and-works-cited&quot;&gt;Further reading and works cited&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://venturebeat.com/2019/07/16/neuralinks-technology-embeds-tiny-wires-in-the-brain-to-read-electrical-pulses/&quot;&gt;VentureBeat on the Neuralink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/07/17/elon-musk-brain-machine-startup-neuralink-plans-human-trials-in-2020.html&quot;&gt;Neuralink plans to start clinical trials by the end of 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuralink&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article describing glial scarring and broken electrodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/brain-machine-interface/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/brain-machine-interface/</guid>
        
        <category>neuroscience</category>
        
        <category>artificial intelligence</category>
        
        
        <category>psychology</category>
        
        <category>essays</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Many Definitions of Intelligence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What was Albert Einstein’s IQ? Many sources online will tell you it was 160. But a quick foray into the supporting evidence for this number reveals that most sources have no scientific proof of Einstein’s IQ score. In fact, 160 may just be a relic of the scale used for measurement: WAIS-IV (Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale 4), probably the most common IQ scoring system, happens to have a max score of — you guessed it — 160. Einstein could be the dictionary definition of genius in today’s society, yet we don’t even know his IQ. How, then, can we be sure of his intelligence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we could look at his creation of a revolutionary new way of understanding the world through theoretical physics. In addition, IQ is a construct related to but separate from intelligence. Given that IQ does not answer our question, how can we truly measure Albert Einstein’s intelligence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many recent critics of IQ have noted (duly), intelligence is a highly complex trait that cannot be reduced to a single score. However, IQ does demonstrate some correlation with job success, as noted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/business-insider/why-iq-big-factor-future-success-job-performance-according-science-research.html&quot;&gt;by Inc magazine&lt;/a&gt;. That is not to say that &lt;em&gt;intelligence&lt;/em&gt; correlates to job success, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What exactly is intelligence, how can we quantify it, and how does it differ from IQ? These are the questions this article will attempt to answer, based on psychological research. After outlining the broad types of intelligence, defining intelligence becomes even more problematic when examining the details. The cultural assumptions inherent in almost all attempts to measure intelligence lead to the formation of problems like exclusivity and perhaps even cultural supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-difference-between-iq-and-intelligence&quot;&gt;What’s the difference between IQ and intelligence?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning with some definitions will help us clarify this discussion. First, IQ (Intelligence Quotient) is an artificial score, much like a high score in Mario Kart, that measures a person’s ability to perform on certain metrics. With Mario Kart, these skills depend on a person’s ability to navigate complex terrain at a high pace, dodging banana peels and throwing turtle shells. IQ tests, meanwhile, measure a person’s aptitude for problem-solving and verbal and spatial skills. Simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intelligence, however, has an deceptively simple definition. Oxford dictionary defines intelligence as “the ability to acquire and apply knowledge and skills.” This statement actually encompasses a vast variety of cognitive skills: memory, flexibility, and focus, just to name a few. Critically, defining intelligence in this way implies its dependence on environmental factors, because evidence has demonstrated that education has a clear influence on an individual’s ability to learn. Environmentally-influenced intelligence is the type that IQ is attempting to measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can we measure intelligence as an intrinsic trait, based in genetics? We start out by recognizing this type of intelligence as separate from the traditional idea of IQ. Let’s call it Intelligence A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;intelligence-a-vs-intelligence-b-vs-intelligence-c&quot;&gt;Intelligence A vs. Intelligence B vs. Intelligence C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more nuanced way of defining intelligence is to realize that there is more than one definition. In a book comparing genetic and environmental determinants of intelligence, Philip Vernon helps define three types of intelligence: Intelligence A is intrinsic. It depends on basic physiological factors like reaction time. Intelligence B includes the effects from the environment. It refers to the application of Intelligence A to the real world, and fits quite well with the Oxford definition of intelligence. Meanwhile, Intelligence C refers to the measurement of intelligence, as in IQ tests. Measured values of intelligence often correlate much more closely with Intelligence B, because it has closely matched the popular conception of intelligence for the last few decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this distinction useful? Intelligence B, while clearly correlated with success, depends on the way a society is structured. In other words, it varies widely between cultures, and therefore between people. In other words, attempts to measure Intelligence B are highly variable and require that a new test is developed for every different culture. Meanwhile, Intelligence A consists of biological skills that should not vary across cultures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s not surprising that IQ tests correlate with success — they reflect traits valued by our society and are therefore strengthened by other success-enhancing factors like education and socioeconomic status. If we want to truly measure the influence of intelligence on success &lt;em&gt;irrespective of culture&lt;/em&gt;, we need to examine the biological basis of intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What exactly does a test of this type look like? The twentieth-century psychologist Hans Eysenck, known especially for his theory of introversion and extroversion, gives a possible example in the form of AEP (Auditory Evoked Potential), a test that allows researchers to measure the reaction time of subjects. He cited preliminary studies that found at least a 0.83 correlation between the AEP results and those of a WAIS test (the standard IQ test mentioned earlier). Apparently, this level of correlation is higher than those between functionally similar IQ tests like the WAIS and Binet tests. However, the study finding this correlation was performed on a notably small sample of individuals; therefore, it poorly represents the vast diversity in levels of education and socioeconomic status around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cultural-result-of-defining-intelligence&quot;&gt;The cultural result of defining intelligence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apa.org/monitor/feb03/intelligence&quot;&gt;this American Psychological Association (APA) cover story&lt;/a&gt;, traditional measures of intelligence translate quite poorly across borders, raising problematic implications for cross-cultural interaction — an IQ test as currently given encapsulates the traits that are considered intelligent &lt;em&gt;in a particular culture&lt;/em&gt;. If a person comes from a culture where those traits are not so valued, they may suddenly find themselves perceived as less intelligent for arbitrary cultural reasons. As noted earlier, IQ is correlated with success, so this cultural disparity may be a major factor behind the cultural barriers to success afflicting diverse modern societies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The APA cover story explains that many psychologists no longer believe in the idea that a test can be completely absent of cultural bias, and probably for good reason. After all, the tests they are thinking of measure &lt;em&gt;Intelligence B&lt;/em&gt;, which by definition encompasses cultural knowledge. Perhaps focusing instead on intelligence A as the standard definition for intelligence, as Hans Eysenck suggested, may be a better way to obviate cultural biases by directly measuring brain activity. Modern brain-scanning technology certainly makes this a promising alternative to current tests. As the world as a whole moves to adopt fair values that appreciate, rather than punish, diversity, intelligence, critical to economic success, should be reconceived in a form that transcends cultural boundaries, as Intelligence A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intelligence, as traditionally defined, represents the sum of myriad genetic and cultural factors, including reaction time, education, socioeconomic status, and so on. Also known as Intelligence B, this is the type of trait commonly measured by IQ tests. Isolating the purely biological elements of intelligence as Intelligence A demonstrates that intelligence does not have to be the politically loaded, culturally and economically insensitive term that it is now, that there is hope for refining our definition of intelligence as both a biological and cultural phenomenon. Only then can we fully acknowledge the potential for growth that our current paradigm ignores all too frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some works that I drew content from, other than those linked in the article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eysenck, H. J. (1988). The biological basis of intelligence. In S. H. Irvine &amp;amp; J. W. Berry (Eds.), Human abilities in cultural context (p. 87–104). Cambridge University Press. https://psycnet.apa.org/record/1988-98683-003&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wikipedia page on Intelligence Quotient: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intelligence_quotient&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oxford Dictionary definition of intelligence: https://www.lexico.com/definition/intelligence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Philip Vernon’s book on intelligence: https://trove.nla.gov.au/work/11823287?q&amp;amp;versionId=45253153&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Definition of cultural intelligence from David C. Thomas: https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118785317.weom060051&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/cultural-intelligence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/cultural-intelligence/</guid>
        
        <category>intelligence</category>
        
        
        <category>psychology</category>
        
        <category>essays</category>
        
        <category>science</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
